Guide to the AIDS/Brookyn Oral History Project collection 1993.001
Brooklyn Historical Society
- John, Marilyn, 1992 June 23; 1993.001.07
  Marilyn John, a Trinidadian woman, was thirty-four year old at the time of the interview in 1992. A graduate of Long Island University, she was once program coordinator for one of the AIDS programs at the Caribbean Women's Health Association (CWHA) in the Flatbush section of Brooklyn. She also had a private AIDS consulting business and represented Caribbean AIDS concerns at the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. John developed insight into the impact AIDS had on the Brooklyn Caribbean communities as well as the experience of AIDS service providers. In the years following this interview, John became executive director of the CWHA and a New York City Department of Health and Mental Hygiene employee. In 2010, John pled guilty in federal court to embezzlement and fraud charges. In 2016, she was the National Ambassadors Coordinator for the faith-based White House Prayer for Our Nation initiative.
  In the interview, Marilyn John speaks extensively on the changes she has witnessed within the Caribbean communities, particularly with regards to sexuality, because of the AIDS crisis. John brings to the conversation her experience from within the Caribbean community, as well as a background and interest in community health. Throughout the course of the interview, John talks about the need for a holistic approach to health (Holistic Methods of Intervention), specifically with a focus on culture and immigration. She also speaks specifically on the need for Caribbean specific cultural training related to HIV. Since her primary interest and expertise is in education, she concentrates on the different approaches she takes to the different needs and characteristics of many of the communities she works with. Finally, she outlines what should be done for Brooklyn's Caribbean communities. Interview conducted by Robert Sember.
  Caribbean Women’s Health Association.; Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (U.S.).; U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services.; AIDS activists |z United States; American Dream |x History |y 20th century; Bedford-Stuyvesant (New York, N.Y.); Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Emigration and immigration; Bushwick (New York, N.Y.); Caribbean Americans; Community activists |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Crown Heights (New York, N.Y.); Epidemics |z United States |x History |y 20th century; HIV-positive persons |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Sexual health |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Stigma (Social psychology) |z New York (State) |z Kings County; United States |x Social policy |x History |y 20th century; Women's health services |z New York (State) |z Kings County
- Morciglio, Adolph, 1992 June 1; 1993.001.08
  In the interview, Adolph Morciglio speaks about his long relationship with drugs; both as a person who used drugs for thirty years and as someone who no longer uses drugs, as well the role that drugs played in his time at Rikers Island. He speaks about his early childhood and the impact he feels it had on his life chances, his early awareness of HIV, the impact HIV has had on his life and his family, as well as the Red Hook community he is from. Towards the end of the interview, he speaks about the need for greater action by the government and churches. Interview conducted by Robert Rosenberg.
  Adolph Morciglio was a person with AIDS (PWA) and a former intravenous drug user (IVDU). Part Puerto Rican, he grew up on Columbia Street in the Red Hook neighborhood of Brooklyn and used to live in the Brooklyn Heights neighborhood at the St. George Hotel in a special program for homeless PWAs. Prior to the interview, he'd had no major opportunistic infections though he had a dangerously low Tcell count. He was formerly working as a paralegal and had served time in prison.
  Brooklyn­Cumberland Medical Center.; Gay Men's Health Crisis, Inc.; Hotel St. George (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).; New York (N.Y.). Department of Social Services.; AIDS (Disease) |x Patients |x Services for |z New York (State) |z New York; AIDS (Disease) |x Patients |x Legal status, laws, etc. |z New York (State); AZT (Drug); Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Drug addiction |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Methadone maintenance |z New York (State) |z New York; Politics and culture |z United States; Prisons |z New York (State); Red Hook (New York, N.Y.); Social justice |z New York (State) |z Kings County; United States |x Emigration and immigration
- Morrissey, Karen and Ripp, Robert, 1992 July 29; 1993.001.09
  Robert (Rob) Ripp is a gay man whose friend and lover Michael died of complications related to HIV/AIDS at the age of twenty-six years old on March 30, 1992. At the time of the interview, Ripp lived in the Park Slope / Carroll Gardens area of Brooklyn and was thirty years old. He grew up on Long Island, and moved to New York when he was twenty-three. In the interview he comes across as both spiritual and political. Ripp was a member of ACT UP. Karen Morrissey is a heterosexual woman, whose brother Michael died of complications related to HIV/AIDS. Morissey is a mother, daughter, sister and teacher in relation to HIV/AIDS.
  This interview focuses on the life, death and relationships of artist and dancer Michael through the point of view of his sister Karen Morrissey and his lover Robert (Rob) Ripp. Together they discuss serodiscordant couples, spirituality in the face of death, the lack of governmental response to HIV/AIDS, witnessing and supporting someone navigating healthcare, and the impact of HIV/AIDS on family, friends and community. Ripp speaks specifically about his understanding of HIV/AIDS as a gay man. Both reflect on being near Michael when he died. Morissey recalls how she came to learn more about homosexuality and HIV/AIDS through her brother and how she was awed by her brother's spirit in the face of adversity. At times, Ripp's and Morrissey's experiences dovetail with one another. Interview conducted by Robert Sember.
  ACT UP New York (Organization).; New York (N.Y.). Department of Social Services.; New York (State). AIDS Institute.; AIDS (Disease) |z New York (State) |z New York; AIDS activists |z United States; Artists |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Carroll Gardens (New York, N.Y.); Family life |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Gays |x Social life and customs; HIV infections |z New York (State) |z New York; HIV-positive persons |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Park Slope (New York, N.Y.); Sexual health |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Stigma (Social psychology) |z New York (State) |z Kings County
- Mulcahy, Donna, 1992 June 27; 1993.001.10
  Donna Mulcahy, a White heterosexual woman, was thirty-one years old in 1992. Her partner Arthur died six months before the interview of AIDS-related causes. While she was born in the South, Mulcahy grew up in Long Island and moved to Brooklyn as an adult, where she met Arthur at a bar on Carroll Street. At the time of the interview, she was a lawyer. Previous to the death of her husband, whose life was impacted by his injection use of heroin, she had been active in the response to AIDS. After his death, Mulcahy was taking time to take care of herself.
  In the interview, Donna Mulcahy discusses her experience as a partnered straight woman not living with HIV in Brooklyn in the early 1990s, married to a man who lived with HIV and an addiction to heroin. The narrator speaks at length throughout the interview about how her partner’s addiction was harder to deal with than his status as an HIV positive person with AIDS. She speaks of a supportive family, a fulfilling work life and a community of people living with and impacted by HIV and addiction. For this narrator, the AIDS crisis was at first something she ignored, then something that was about people who used drugs and were dying, and eventually about other communities such as gay men and other partners of people living with HIV. Interview conducted by Robert Sember.
  AIDS (Disease) |z New York (State) |z New York; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Carroll Gardens (New York, N.Y.); Drug addiction |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Family life |z New York (State) |z Kings County; HIV infections |z New York (State) |z New York; HIV-positive persons |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Park Slope (New York, N.Y.); Sexual health |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Social group work |z New York (State); Stigma (Social psychology) |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Women's health services |z New York (State) |z Kings County
- N., A., 1992 May 4; 1993.001.11
  A woman living with HIV/AIDS, A.N. was forty-three years old at the time of the inter-view in 1992. Originally from Grenada, she moved with her family to Brooklyn when she was ten months old. After a break up with her partner of seventeen years, she moved to California where, within a few years, she found out she was living with what she called “full blown AIDS.” The interview took place in the house she grew up in, where she lives with her family who help care for her.
  In the interview, A.N. discusses the life of a single Black woman living with HIV/AIDS in Brooklyn. The narrator speaks clearly throughout about her health challenges, weaving together her time in California and her time in Brooklyn. She speaks specifically about the Brooklyn neighborhood of Crown Heights in relation to people’s ideas of who has HIV, and who doesn't. She also speaks at some length about sexuality, race, and HIV. Towards the end of the recording, an unidentified second interviewer comes in. Interview conducted by Robert Rosenberg.
  AIDS (Disease) |z New York (State) |z New York; AZT (Drug); Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); California; Crown Heights (New York, N.Y.); Family life |z New York (State) |z Kings County; HIV infections |z New York (State) |z New York; HIV-positive persons |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Sexual health |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Social group work |z New York (State); Stigma (Social psychology) |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Women's health services |z New York (State) |z Kings County
- Norris, Barbara, 1992 August 19; 1993.001.12
  Barbara Norris was a nurse working at Woodhull Hospital in the Bushwick neighborhood of Brooklyn, where she worked at the AIDS clinic. Born in Harlem, New York, she moved to Brooklyn when she was married, had three sons, and two grandchildren. At the time of the interview in 1992, she was a woman of Christian faith whose experience with people living with HIV at the hospital helped shape her view on homosexuals, people who do drugs and other members of the community.
  In the interview Barbara Norris speaks about her experience as a nurse from the 1970s to the early 1990s in Brooklyn, whose work has been deeply impacted by HIV. She speaks at length about the virus’ impact on the people of Brooklyn, who she saw coming into the hospital. At times she briefly mentions differences within the epidemic in Brooklyn compared to Manhattan. Due to the narrator’s long standing perspective as a nurse with various high positions, she is able to share ideas on the role of the hospital within the epidemic and what ought to be happening. Norris also shares insights into the emotional toll the epidemic has on nurses. Interview conducted by Robert Rosenberg.
  Woodhull Medical and Mental Health Center (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).; AIDS (Disease) |x Information services; AIDS (Disease) |x Patients |x Services for |z New York (State) |z New York; AIDS activists |z United States; AZT (Drug); Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); HIV infections |z New York (State) |z New York; HIV-positive persons |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Nurses |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Social group work |z New York (State); Stigma (Social psychology) |z New York (State) |z Kings County
- Palazzo, Maria, 1992 July 30; 1993.001.13
  Maria Palazzo is a White Italian woman from the Sunset Park neighborhood of Brooklyn who, at the time of this interview, was a volunteer at Gay Men’s Health Crisis (GMHC). She began volunteering for the AIDS Walk and other fundraisers; jobs in line with her paid work as an accountant in Manhattan, and eventually became part of the GMHC Buddy Program. Palazzo went on to do more outreach-based work.
  In the interview, Maria Palazzo provides a view of what it was to be a volunteer with a large AIDS organization in a major city in the United States in the 1990s. She speaks about the her motivations for volunteering, her interactions with fellow volunteers, and the reactions she gets from the general public, her workmates, friends, and family related to her volunteering. The narrator also considers differences in attitudes and available resources between Manhattan and the Bronx. Interview conducted by Robert Sember.
  Gay Men's Health Crisis, Inc.; AIDS (Disease) |x Information services; AIDS (Disease) |x Patients |x Services for |z New York (State) |z New York; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Family life |z New York (State) |z Kings County; HIV infections |z New York (State) |z New York; HIV-positive persons |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Social group work |z New York (State); Stigma (Social psychology) |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Voluntarism |z New York (State) |z Kings County
- Pearson, Mildred, 1992 July 11; 1993.001.14
  Sixty-one years old at the time of the interview in 1992, Mildred Pearson was an African-American woman from the Williamsburg neighborhood of Brooklyn. She was born and raised in Brooklyn's Boerum Hill neighborhood. At Cooper Park public housing, she and her second husband Rutledge raised fourteen children born out of three marriages. Her experience as a mother of a gay son who died of AIDS prompted her to join the Brooklyn AIDS Task Force (BATF), using the story of the loss to communicate information about AIDS. Realizing that more than education was needed to meet the emotional stress experienced by persons with AIDS (PWAs) and their families, Pearson left BATF to establish a support group for mothers of PWAs. Mother's Love had weekly meetings for its members/mothers who engaged in extensive outreach work in Brooklyn and the other boroughs. Mildred Pearson died in April, 1994.
  In the interview, Mildred Pearson discusses the personal knowledge that came out of being a mother of a person with AIDS (PWA) and working as a care provider. Pearson chronicles the experience of discovering that her son Bruce Williams was sick, the efforts in his treatment, and the home care that had a demonstrative effect on his health. In the wake of Williams' death, she recalls getting help from a volunteer who had befriended Williams. She discusses reaching out to tell her story in support of the Brooklyn AIDS Task Force. In search of a support group for mothers that felt more inclusive and diverse, she tells of forming the Mother's Love group. Pearson describes her development into an activist without a hard-edged militant stance. She touches on many bases that reflected society's responses to the AIDS crisis in the late 1980s and early 1990s. Pearson speaks concretely about health care, social services, and the emotions generated by illness and loss. Pearson also recalls sensing a more tolerant period in her Brooklyn youth. Before ending on a note about the strength she receives from her faith, she takes a view on society's ills of homelessness and addiction and relates those challenges to other human losses that her family has suffered. Interview conducted by Robert Sember.
  Brooklyn AIDS Task Force.; Gay Men's Health Crisis, Inc.; African Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County; AIDS (Disease) |z New York (State) |z New York; AIDS activists |z New York (State) |z New York; AIDS-related complex |x Treatment |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Boerum Hill (New York, N.Y.); Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Family life |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Funeral rites and ceremonies |z New York (State) |z Kings County; HIV-positive persons |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Self-help groups |z New York (State) |z New York; Social group work |z New York (State)
- Post, Kenny and Wagner, Cheryl, 1992 September 25; 1993.001.15
  Cheryl Wagner and Kenny Post, both White and Brooklynites by birth, had married four years before this 1992 interview. They met at a Narcotics Anonymous social shortly after they had begun rehabilitation programs for IV drug users. At the time of their meeting, Post already knew he was HIV positive. Wagner was tested a year or two later and discovered that she too was positive. They had both experienced AIDS related illnesses. Post worked as a cab driver, identified as an activist and attended AIDS Coalition to Unleash Power (ACT UP) meetings. Wagner had participated in a variety of AIDS support/activist groups. They were both using Gay Men's Health Crisis resources. Her fifteen year old son was living with the couple in a home in the Sheepshead Bay neighborhood of Brooklyn in 1992. Before their marriage and AIDS, both Wagner's and Post's lives revolved around drug use.
  In the interview, Kenny Post and Cheryl Wagner share strong opinions about the particular issues that HIV raises for addicts and are critical of many of the programs established for this population. In addition, Wagner is concerned about AIDS as a woman's issue and presents numerous examples, many of them personal, of the ignorance and discrimination faced by women with AIDS. They both are incisively critical of the healthcare and welfare system in New York City and the inadequate and unequal distribution of resources across the boroughs. Finally, they are people with AIDS who are involved in an intimate and caring relationship and their discussion of this aspect of their lives provides a particular perspective on the emotional impact of the AIDS crisis in the twentieth century. Interview conducted by Robert Sember.
  ACT UP New York (Organization).; Gay Men's Health Crisis, Inc.; New York (N.Y.). Department of Social Services.; AIDS (Disease) |z New York (State) |z New York; AIDS activists |z New York (State) |z New York; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Drug addiction |z New York (State) |z Kings County; HIV-positive persons |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Self-help groups |z New York (State) |z New York; Sexual health |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Sheepshead Bay (New York, N.Y.); Social group work |z New York (State); Stigma (Social psychology) |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Williamsburg (New York, N.Y.); Women's health services |z New York (State) |z Kings County
- Rivera, Dolores, 1992 September 11; 1993.001.16
  Dolores Rivera, a fifty-one year old Irish and African-American woman, was diagnosed with AIDS after a bout of pneumocystis pneumonia in 1986. Rivera was raised in Brooklyn’s Brownsville neighborhood. Except for a brief stint in Staten Island, she lived in Brooklyn. With all of children grown into young adults, at thirty-six she began abusing drugs, became an addict and went through years as a homeless IV drug user. She believed she was infected with HIV through IV drug use, although she knew that her last sexual encounter was with a man who had the virus. After her HIV positive diagnosis; she went into rehab, got off the streets and began outreach work within the Brooklyn IV drug-using community. When this interview took place in 1992, she had an apartment in Bensonhurst. Rivera was babysitting one granddaughter daily, including while this interview was recorded. By 2004, the year she died, she had served on the Board of Directors at Iris House.
  In the interview, Dolores Rivera tells her story of childhood in an abusive home and how that profoundly affected her adulthood. Besides her vivid descriptions of her years as a homeless IV drug user, she reflects on how she felt and thought about herself. She discusses how her life changed remarkably after her diagnosis. Rivera shares her awareness of AIDS issues and gives her impression of the different impacts that AIDS has had on various Brooklyn communities. She also has some ideas about what should be done to better manage the crisis. The interview is occasionally interrupted by Rivera’s childcare. Interview conducted by Robert Sember.
  ACT UP New York (Organization).; Gay Men's Health Crisis, Inc.; AIDS (Disease) |z New York (State) |z New York; AIDS activists |z New York (State) |z New York; Bensonhurst (New York, N.Y.); Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Drug addiction |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Family life |z New York (State) |z Kings County; HIV-positive persons |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Homeless women |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Self-help groups |z New York (State) |z New York; Social group work |z New York (State); Stigma (Social psychology) |z New York (State) |z Kings County
- Rosa, Luis Nieves, 1992 July 11; 1993.001.17
  An HIV positive and healthy Puerto Rican gay man, Dr. Luis Nieves Rosa was thirty-three years old in 1992. Raised in Arecibo, Puerto Rico, he moved to San Juan in 1977. Being openly gay since age eighteen, he was convinced later that he had contracted the virus through sex in 1985 or earlier. He moved to Brooklyn in 1988 and lived in the Fort Greene neighborhood when the interview took place. From 1988-1990, he was a caseworker for people with AIDS (PWAs) at Woodhull Hospital in the Bushwick neighborhood of Brooklyn. It was during this period that his roommate and good friend got sick and died of AIDS, and Nieves Rosa was a major care-partner for him. Later, he was working at the Hispanic AIDS Forum, and was active with Latino Gay Men of New York on gay and AIDS issues. He had completed a doctoral program in social work at the University of Puerto Rico, where he also teaches, and in 2012 he published on the subject of homophobia in universities. As of 2014, he was serving as Director of the Center for Applied Social Research in Puerto Rico.
  Luis Nieves Rosa is interviewed about his young adult life as a gay man in Puerto Rico and the four years, prior to this 1992 interview, spent in Brooklyn. He speaks generally about the issues of Latino and gay Latino people with AIDS from his work with the Hispanic AIDS Forum. He weaves together four strands of his story: a gay Latin man who is HIV positive (he participated in an experimental drug study), a care-partner for a friend who died of AIDS, and a service provider and activist on AIDS issues. Interview conducted by Robert Rosenberg.
  Hispanic AIDS Forum.; Woodhull Medical and Mental Health Center (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).; AIDS (Disease) |z New York (State) |z New York; AIDS activists |z New York (State) |z New York; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Bushwick (New York, N.Y.); HIV-positive persons |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Hospitals |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Puerto Ricans |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Puerto Rico; Self-help groups |z New York (State) |z New York; Social group work |z New York (State); Social workers |z New York (State) |z New York; Stigma (Social psychology) |z New York (State) |z Kings County
- Sandoval, William with Rodriguez, Rita, 1992 June 11; 1993.001.18